Okay, so we are doing X in the grade today.
好的，今天我们在做X。
Let us review last class
OK?
where
...
we discussed the father -son dynamic between Philip II and his son Alexander.
我们讨论了菲利普二世与他的儿子亚历山大之间的父子关系。
We said that the father,
We said that thefather,
he is the founder
...
and the builder of a great organization
翻译
and
...
as such he will have three particular characteristics unique to him.
作为此类的前景，...
First of all, he will exercise really good judgment
...
because he's starting with nothing and
he has to build up slowly his nation or his organization.
...
Second thing that
we said is he will promote talent.
我们已经说过他会发掘人才。
He will be a very generous and
他将非常慷慷
fair -minded individual who
...
will actively spot talent and create a meritocracy. Okay,
将主动发掘人才并创建精英制。
the third thing we said was this person will be selfless,
the third thing we said wasthis person will be selfless,
extremely disciplined and
...
this person will put the greater good before his or her own interests.
这位 ? ?? ?? ?? ??? ? ???????
Okay, and that will inspire loyalty from his or her workers or soldiers.
好的，...
We also said the son will be very different.
...
Okay, because the son is inheriting this enterprise or this nation.
好的，因为儿子继承这事业或这国度。
The son will focus on expansion.
好的，儿子会把握手握握手
The son will be a very aggressive risk -taker.
...
Okay, second characteristic of the son is
OK
because he is under the father's shadow,
...
he will promote obedience and loyalty.
Promote loyalty. And
...
the final characteristic, the final contrast between the father and
the final...
son is the son will be very selfish
...
because of the father's integrity.
因为父亲的...
The son will be focused on personal glory.
子曰：专注个人荣耀。
The reason why is the son is insecure, right?
子曰：因其自我…
The son will hear people in the background and shadows
子在背景与阴影中听到人们低声细语，“我已完成的事，都是因父亲而已。”
whispering, oh, everything you've achieved is because of your father.
子在…
And so the son is desperate,
...
very anxious to prove his own self -worth.
Okay, so we see this
好的，先看这
dynamic in literature and in history.
OK
That's important, or or or or or or or or or or or or or
...
or or or or or or or or or or
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or
翻译：
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or
or or
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or have to test
翻译：
which true or not and
if it's true it does two things okay
...
first thing it does is it explains
does it help us understand better understand the motivations
...
and behavior of people around us and
last class we thought we focused on for the second and
???
we and that really helped us to understand his motivations
...
and behavior okay today but the second thing it must do is predict
okay it has to predict the future if this analytical model
...
that we have is correct and
那我们已经有的模型是正确的
it will allow us to predict future events
它将使我们能够预测未来事件
and behavior okay and
]}
that's what I propose today I propose to use
...
this model to predict the life of academic great okay
so
...
from this model we
从此模型可推算三种特征
can extrapolate three characteristics of
Alexander's reign when
...
he takes over as king okay um
what's the first characteristic of Alexander
...
when he when he becomes
king okay
...
I go do you have any ideas of
I go do you haveany ideas of
what he will do as king exactly okay
...
so the first thing we will
say is that he will focus on
expansion okay he'll be a
very aggressive risk taker you will take risks that
are not strategically wise okay that's the first prediction
...
we can make about him what's the second prediction
we can make about him based on
this exactly
...
we call this a tyrant okay he's gonna be
kind of like a tyrant or
翻译成中文
or or or or or
?? ? ?? ?? ? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ... ?? ??? ??? ?? ??? ?? ??? ?? ??? ?? ? ??? ?? ??? ?? ??? - ???? ??? ?? - ??????????????????????????? 1 ?? ?????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
or or or or or or or or or or or
or or or or or or or or or
...
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or
or or or or or or oror or or or or or or
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or
...
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or
or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or or
或...
because he's telling people will counter his tyranny.
因为...
So we predict he will demand complete
所以我们预测他会要求完全
and total obedience from his followers.
并且...
And what's the third prediction we can make about him?
??
Well, the third prediction is that he,
the question is, will he ever be happy?
...
When will he stop his ambition?
Never, okay? So his ambition is boundless.
??
So these are the three predictions we can make about Alexander if he were to become king,
...
just based on our understanding of the father -son dynamic, okay?
}]
The first is that he will focus on aggressive expansion.
...
He will take risks that his father will not take, okay?
他会做出父亲未曾尝试的风险，好的？
That's the first thing. Second thing is, he's gonna become a tyrant who will demand
他会...??
total loyalty and obedience from his followers.
??
And if you, for his own good,
speak up and try to reason with him,
说起来，尝试与他商量，
he will see you as a threat, as disloyal,
?
and as an enemy who must be eliminated, okay?
和作为必须消灭的敌人，好的？
The third prediction we can make is,
第三个预测是，
his ambition is boundless.
他的雄心无边。
He will never stop expanding.
他永不停止扩张。
He will never stop going to war, okay?
他永不停止出战，OK吗？
These are the three predictions we can make based on this analytical model, okay?
这些是根据此分析模型可做出的三预测。
And it turns out, these three predictions
翻译：
basically cap to the essence of Alexander's life, okay?
??
All right? So
...
now I will slowly explain the life and times of Alexander the Great.
现在我慢慢地说说亚历山大一世的生活与时光。
All right, so any questions so far?
...
Okay, so we are using this analytical model
好的，我们用这个分析模型
to understand the life and times of Alexander the Great.
好的，使用此分析模型
And while we're doing this,
当我们做这件事时，
we're trying to see if there are problems with this model, okay?
我们正尝试着去看…
All right, so we have to take a very skeptical attitude.
好的，我们要以非常怀疑的姿态来做事。
We have this prediction model.
我们有这预测模型。
We're gonna apply it to Alexander the Great, and
我们将把它应用于亚历山大大帝，且…
we're gonna see that on the surface,
…
it does actually capture well, or explains well his life.
它确实能很好地捕捉/解释…
At the same time, we want to be generous and skeptical, okay?
…
We want to ask ourselves, is it possible that
我们想问自己，是否可能我们已被先前的偏见所蒙蔽，且…
we are blinded by our prejudice, and
我们要点个别的…
maybe we are being unfair to Alexander the Great, okay?
…
Does that make sense? All right, so
let's start with the first major event in Alexander the Great's life,
? …… ? …
which is the death of his father in 3 3 C BCE,
……
okay? And Alexander right now, he's only 20, and when his father dies, he is, he's dead.
OK? 先前……………………………………
He is automatically coronated as king of,
]}We need to translate cues 132-134. Provide JSON with translations array. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Use simplified Chinese. Use terms: Macedon -> 马其国? Actually
the kingdom of Macedon. Now, I want to explain the circumstances of Philip's death,
? Wait. The term
because it's very important for us to understand the sort of psychology of his son.
因为这对我们理解他儿子的心理很重要。
So, two years before his death,
于是，二年前他去世前，菲利普再次结婚。
Philip actually remarried, okay?
菲利普的妻子们都已是…
Now, remember that Macedon is a society
...
that promotes polygamy, okay?
So, Philip, at this point, already has six or seven wives.
...
The problem is that only one of his wives,
141. 只是一位妻子，
named Olympias, has given birth to a son,
141. ? ? ? ?? ? ..?? ?? ? ?? ?? -?? …… ? 问题 ? ? … … … ?? … 中… ? ?? ...?? “… … Olymp … … 问题… .. … 中…… 只… … “…… … JSON… .. -……………………………………………
and therefore a heir, okay? The son is Alexander.
翻译后...………………………………………………
The other wives have failed to give birth to a heir,
]}We need to translate cues 143 and 144. Provide JSON array translations. Each string may contain at most one newline. Use natural Chinese. Let's translate: cue 143:
and it seems Alexander will be anointed king at the death of his father.
...
So, when Philip marries,
her name is Cleopatra Eurydice,
...
and it's extremely controversial,
okay? And it sort of disrupts the political order of Macedonia.
好的，...…………………………………………………………
The first reason is Cleopatra Eurydice,
?
she is actually Macedonian.
她实际上是马其达人。
Before, Philip married foreign wives for diplomacy reasons.
在前面，菲利普先前往外面嫁给了外面嫁给了外面嫁给了外面嫁给了外面嫁后…
And what this means is,
if Cleopatra Eurydice gives birth to a son,
if Cleopatra Eurydicegives birth to a son,
this son will be more legitimate
...
here than Alexander.
这里有亚历山大。
And this pushes Alexander out of the line of succession.
这里的...??
So, this is extremely controversial,
所以，这非常有争议，
and it's like dynamite almost, okay?
所以这点儿很大…
So, that's the first problem. Second problem is,
...
Eurydice is the wife of one of Philip's great generals,
Attalus. And
阿特拉斯。然后…
actually, at the wedding ceremony between Eurydice
Eur‑?
and Philip, Attalus gave a toast, and he said, I'm going to marry you.
164. 以及...??…
Here's a toast, and I pray that
]}We need to translate cues 164 and 165. Let's read them: [164] and Philip,Attalus gave a toast, and he said, I'm going to marry... Wait actual text:
Macedon will soon have a legitimate heir.
马可多很快就有合法继承人了。
And this is a direct insult to Alexander, okay?
...
The other problem is that Attalus,
其他问题是阿特拉斯，
his father -in -law, is Parmenion, who
他父亲-??…
is really Philip's partner, okay?
他父亲…
The greatest general that Macedon has,
...??…
the person in control of the army, okay?
So, it seems like,
...??...
Alexander is being pushed out of the line of succession.
...
And Alexander and his mother, Olympias, are both freaking out, okay?
So, in 336 BCE,
...
Philip is assassinated by his bodyguard.
菲利普被随从杀死了。
And no one knows why this happened, okay?
随便的??…
But we know what happened.
我…??…
Afterwards, what happened is, first of all, Olympias,
之后，先是奥利米亚斯先去掉了
killed Eurydice and
...
her daughter and son.
The son was going to be legitimate heir to the throne.
子嗣将成为王位合法继承者。
Now, they're all dead, okay?
????????????????????????????????????????
That's the first thing that happens. Second thing that happens is,
????????????????????????????
Attalus becomes afraid, and he's about to rebel, okay?
...
And Attalus, again, is a general.
At this stage, at this point,
...
Parmenion is now the kingmaker, right?
Because Parmenion is now the kingmaker. He's now head of the army.
???
He can choose to support Attalus, his son -in -law,
and rebel, okay?
和起义，好吗？
And maybe become king himself.
又可成为王子。
Or he can support Alexander, okay?
或可支持亚历山大，OK?
And at this point, the faithful decision that
...
Parmenion makes is, he supports Alexander and he kills Attalus.
帕尔梅尼翁成了他，支持亚历山大并杀了阿塔卢斯。
And Attalus, again, is his son -in -law.
阿塔卢斯又是他的女婿。
And this makes Alexander now the legitimate heir to Philip.
并且这使得亚历山大成为菲利浦的合法继承者。
He's now king of Assyria. Okay?
他已是阿萨里亚王。
So, from this event,
从此事件开始，
we can surmise some things, okay?
The first thing we can surmise is,
202 的 前景 作 好 后 后 后 后 后 后 后 后后 后 推 后 后 1 后 后 后 后 后 202 后 …
Olympias and Alexander are extremely ambitious,
202 后 后 1 后 i i后 后 i JSON i…
right? They will not be pushed aside.
右？他们不被推到一边。
If they see any risk to their power,
如果你们能看到…
they will act viciously.
先前…
Okay? They're not afraid to kill.
好的？他们不怕杀人。
They will even kill the king in order to address the king.
他们会把它们的前后…
And they will not be able to assure their power.
...
Okay? That's the first thing. The second thing that's more important for us is,
好的？那是第一件事。第二件事更好…
Parmenion is absolutely
Paman…
loyal to Alexander.
...
Because, if you think about it, he's loyal to the memory of Philip.
因为，如果你想想，菲尔普斯忠于菲尔普斯的记忆。
Okay? Philip promoted Parmenion to be his partner.
?好??????????????????????????????????
And in a show of loyalty and gratitude,
]}We need to produce translations for cues 213-215. Provide JSON with translations array of 3 strings. Use simplified Chinese. Use line breaks if needed. Let's translate each cue properly. Use terms:
Parmenion now is being loyal to the son, Alexander.
帕尔梅尼翁现在忠于亚历山大之子。
Okay? So, that's the first major event in Alexander's life.
好的，……
Any questions about this event?
…
Before I move on? Okay.
So, the second thing that happens is, remember, like,
So...????????????????
Philip is now in charge of this white kingdom across Greece.
...?????????
And when people hear about his death,
当人们听到他的去世时，
people start to rebel.
人们开始起义。
Okay? The Athenians want to rebel.
好的？雅典人想起义。
The Thebans want to rebel. The Spartans want to rebel.
底下百里里，百里百里…
And then to the north, the Illyrians rebel.
然后到北方，伊利里人起义。
Okay? So, there are these rebellions.
好的？我们来回顾一下！
The first thing that Alexander does is,
第一个动作是，亚历山大做的事是，
he mounts this extremely fast
第一个动作是，亚历决胜
and decisive campaign to quell all eternal dissent.
和决定性的战役以平息所有永恒的纷争。
Because, ultimately, his ambition is to complete the dream of his father,
因为…
the conquest of Persia. Right?
征服波斯的事，没错吗？
So, he goes to Illyria, which is in north.
先后…
Which is north to Macedonia.
哪一方在北方是马其达。
And destroys all opposition.
并且把所有的前方。
Next thing he does is, he marches against Greece itself.
接着他去往格里亚。
Against Thebes. And
对底比斯。然后
Thebes is the main source of opposition.
底比斯是主要的反对方。
And Sparta and Athens both promised to send troops to support Thebes.
又有斯巴达与巴斯特。
The problem is, Alexander gets there really fast.
问题在于亚历山大到达时很快。
And he lays siege to Thebes and destroys it completely.
翻译后句子句后再写后续句后写后续后写后续句后写后后写后后??
The next thing that he does is,
?
he decides to massacre all the males and enslave all the women.
他决定全部杀死男士并奴役女儿。
Now, this is actually common practice back then in terms of warfare.
现在，回到古代战争里，回到古语句式…
But this is not done to Greek cities.
“…”
Do you understand? The Greeks considered themselves special.
Do you...?
And so, in 404 BCE,
?
when Sparta defeated Athens in the Peloponnesian War,
remember that Sparta did not do anything.
记得，萨拉发不做什么事。
Sparta just basically said, guys, will you promise not to bother us again?
萨拉发只要说：……
And Athens says, we promise. That was it.
可是……
Okay? So, what Alexander the Great did,
好的？那么，亚历山大大帝所作的事，
destroying Thebes, which
大破坏了百色之…
is one of the great cultural centers of the Greek world,
...
that was like basically setting off a nuclear bomb.
那就像是点燃了核弹一样。
Okay? And from then on, the Greeks were committed to overthrowing Alexander
好的？从此以后，希腊人就决定在机会出现时推翻亚历山大。
when the opportunity arose. At the same time,
与此同时，
Alexander, by doing this, by showing his ruthlessness,
亚历山大，做这件事后，给他人们的又一次…
he was able to, for now,
...………………
pacify all discontent.
……… … ……
People are now afraid of him.
人们现在开始畏惧他。
And that's what Alexander wants.
他又是要的那点儿。
He wants fear. Okay.
他想要点儿…
So, now that eternal dissent has been pacified,
现在，永久的...
now that
...
his leadership has been legitimized,
he will now embark on the massive invasion of Athens.
他会...
The invasion of Persia. Okay?
...
Now, originally his father,
Philip II,
his dream was a unified Greek world.
他的梦...
Okay? What we call Hellenistic.
...
Okay? Or the Hellenic world.
好的？或者希腊世界。
Because remember, at this point, you have these Greek -Polish
因为…………………
that spread all across the Aegean and the Mediterranean.
…
Okay? In North Africa, in Italy, in Asia Minor,
好的？在北非、意大利、亚细小洲，在安塔洛亚。好的，菲利普的梦是统一这几处…】}We need to translate cues 276-278. Provide Chinese subtitles. Use line breaks natural. Let's translate each cue separately,maintain order. Provide array of strings. Each string may contain at most one newline. Let's produce translations. Use simplified Chinese. Let's produce: cue 276:
in Anatolia. Okay? And
Wait we need totranslate:
Philip's vision was to unify all these places.
? Let's read cue276:
But Alexander the Great, his vision was actually to conquer Persia.
在安塔洛斯…??
Okay? So he's expanding his father's vision.
好的，先前已在安塔洛斯……
So he's landing, he lands in Anatolia,
?
which is like modern -day Turkey, with this massive invasion force.
在安塔洛斯…??
Okay? And he's going against the Persian Empire.
The way that the Persian Empire is designed is,
帕萨鲁的设计方式是，
it's not really an empire, it's more like a confederation or alliance.
帕萨里…
So, the provincial governors, who we call the satraps,
所以，省级总督——我们称之为萨特拉普——就是负责守护自己领土的官员。
they're the ones responsible for defending their own territory.
And at this point, the king of Persia,
???
his name is Darius III,
他名字是Dauris 3??
he's not really bothered by Alexander.
...
Okay? He doesn't realize that
OK? 这位……
Alexander will pose a threat to his rule.
??
Okay? He just thinks this guy, he's like 20 years old,
OK? 他只要点儿…??
he's an upstart, he doesn't really matter.
他是个起始点，...
So Darius doesn't really bother himself.
...
Okay? But he sends an advisor. This guy, he's a Greek,
好的？但他派了一个顾问。这个人是希腊人，
Menon of Rhodes.
梅农·罗德斯的
So he's Greek, and he understands Greek warfare.
...
And so, they have this war council between the satraps,
the local governors, and Menon of Rhodes. And
当地的统治者，和罗德斯的梅农。
what Menon of Rhodes proposes is a safer strategy to defeat Alexander,
梅农·罗德斯的提出的方案是把它们放在一起，算作…
which is basically what we call a war of attrition.
哪一条是基本上我们所说的消耗战。
And the idea is they will not encounter,
And the idea is theywill not encounter,
not fight, Alexander on the battlefield.
不战，亚历山大在战场。
Because Alexander right now possesses the greatest army in the world.
因为亚历山大此时拥有最强军队。
Right? Let's not fight him.
对了！我们不再去打他了。
We will burn all the crops and starve his troops.
我们会把所有的草料吃掉，算作…
At the same time, what we will do is we will bribe Athens
同一时间，我们会给亚里士多夫人去…
and Sparta to rebel against Alexander.
...
And once he's overextended, he has no choice but to go home.
Okay? The war is over.
好的？战争结束了。
It doesn't cost us anything.
它不再给我们任何东西。
Okay? The satraps refuse this plan
好的？萨特拉普斯...
because it would mean destroying their own property.
因为会把它们的财产毁掉。
Okay? So satraps are like, no.
好的，………………
We can overwhelm him.
我们可以把它们……………
So the Battle of Granaticus in 334 BCE,
格兰纳提库斯之战于公元前334年发生，
Alexander's forces destroy the Persians.
亚历山大军队在此时刻把百里士兵军队消灭。
Okay? And this is the first major battle of this war.
好的，...这场战斗的第一场大战。”}]}We need to translate cues 317-319 into Simplified Chinese. Provide array of translations in order. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Use preferred terms. Let's translate each cue properly. Use natural Chinese subtitles. Let's produce translations. Ensure each string is a subtitle line. Let's produce three translations. Let's craft them. Use
There will be three major battles. What's important for us is during this battle,
有三场主要战役。对我们而言，关键在于这场战役中，
Alexander displayed tremendous recklessness.
亚历山大展现出惊人的冲劲。
Okay? He rushed to the front of the battle.
好吧？他冲向战役前线。
He led his cavalry and he was almost overwhelmed.
他率领骑兵，几乎被压倒。
Okay? One of the satraps knocked him down.
好吧？一名属领把他击倒。
One of the satraps was about to kill him, slash him.
一名属领正准备砍他。
Okay? But then at the last minute, a man named Plitus the Black,
译文1
Plitus the Black,
译文2
comes running in and he slashes,
译...
he cuts off the satraps' arm.
他把属领的手臂切断。
Thus saving Alexander's life.
从而救了亚历山大一命。
All right? So at this point, there are two individuals
此时有两个人。
that Alexander should be most grateful for.
Right? Parmonion, who basically,
he was a kingmaker
译文3
and he announced that the army would be always loyal to Alexander.
335. 译文1
Okay? And Plitus the Black, who
335. 译?????????????????????????
saved Alexander's life in battle. And
?
both of these men were individuals
这两位都是才子
promoted heavily by his father for their talent.
他们被父亲大力提拔
Okay? So basically, it was his father's man that saved Alexander.
好的，基本上就是父亲的手下人
So you would think Alexander would be very grateful to these men.
所以你会认为亚历山大会非常感激这两位人。
Right? Unfortunately,
右好吧? … … … … … …?? … … … c…?
he would end up killing both men.
?? … ?? ?? ?? …? … ..???
And this would forever change the course of his life.
它将永远改变他人生的轨迹。
Okay? All right. So,
好的？好了。于是……
after the Battle of Granaticus,
在格兰塔基斯战役之后，
Menna Rhodes was given
梅娜·罗德斯获得了
complete freedom to do what he wanted.
完整的自由去做他想做的事。
So Menna Rhodes tried to stop Alexander.
于是梅娜·罗德斯试图阻止亚历山大。
And when he realized he couldn't do it because Alexander's army was too powerful,
当他发现他能否能用...??
Menna Rhodes set sail for Greece.
]}??????????????????????????????????????…
He was hoping to bribe Athens and
.????????????格??..?????…
Sparta to join the war and rebel against Alexander.
斯帕塔加入战争并反对亚历山大。
And here, something that happens.
这里有个好事发生了。
And Alexander gets really lucky.
亚历山大又一次又回到回到??
Okay? And we will find this in his life.
好的？我们会在他的生涯中找到这个。
He gets very lucky a lot of times.
他很久很久后又一次又回到回到??
And what is it that happens when Menna Rhodes sets sail for Greece?
...
About to, and he's about to unite the Greeks and rebel against Alexander.
即将要，...
And remember, Athens and Sparta at this point really hates Alexander.
...
So what happens? He dies.
Okay? He gets sick and he dies.
好的？他生病后去世。
And when Menna Rhodes dies,
当马尼拉·罗德斯去世时，
there's no more contact with the Greek world.
此时已无与希腊世界的联系。
And now Persia is left to basically defend itself.
现在波斯基本上要自卫之时。
Okay? The Greeks cannot be counted on.
好吧！……………
There will be Greek rebellions against Alexander, but they will be sporadic.
此时………………
They will not be coordinated. Okay?
他们不会协调。好吧？
So Darius has no choice but to confront Alexander in two massive battles.
所以大卫王没有选择，只能在两场大规模战斗中与亚历山大对决。
So the first massive battle is in southern Turkey.
于是第一场大规模战斗在南方土耳其。
Anatolia caught the Battle of Isis.
安塔利亚捕捉伊西战斗。
Okay? In 333 BCE.
好吧！在333年BCE。
The second battle will happen two
第二场战斗将会两
years later in Guacamole in Mesopotamia.
几年后，在美索波特米亚的瓜卡莫里。
And both of these battles are about the same.
两场战斗都相同。
Okay? So I will explain what happened in both battles.
我会解释两场战斗的事情。
So you're going to understand Alexander's strategy of war.
所以你会理解亚历山大战争策略。
All right. So usually in battles,
好的，通常在战斗里，
there are three major forces.
有三种主要力量。
There's something called the left flank.
有一个叫做左翼的东西
Okay? The center flank and the right flank.
一条好句子？
And both armies are like this.
...
Now, in both battles,
现在，在两场战斗里，
the Persians were heavily outnumbered the Greeks,
帕里士人比希腊人多了两倍。
two to one. Okay? So it's a massive difference.
两倍的...
And the cavalry is usually on the sides.
骑兵通常在两侧。
Now, there are some certain differences.
现在有一些差异。
Okay? The first difference is the Persians have one leader, Darius.
好的，帕里士人有一位领袖，达里斯。
And he's in the center being protected by his bodyguard called the Immortals.
他在中间，身后有护卫，称为不朽兵。
The Immortals are the best troops of the Persians.
不朽兵是帕里士人最好的兵种。
Okay? The Macedonians have two leaders.
好，麦德里亚人有两位领袖。
Parmonion and Alexander.
帕尔蒙尼翁与亚历山大
Alexander is in charge of the cavalry.
亚历山大负责骑兵
Parmonion is in charge of the infantry.
帕尔蒙尼翁负责步兵
What we call the phalanx.
我们称之为方阵。
And in both battles, the same thing happens.
在两场战斗里，都是同样的事。
Which is, on the left side,
在左侧的方阵里…
Darius commits most of his forces against Parmonion.
帕尔蒙尼翁的军队向帕尔蒙尼翁投身。
Okay? So Parmonion is being overwhelmed by superior numbers.
好的，帕尔左侧…
But here, the discipline is different.
其…
The discipline of Parmonion is just incredible.
帕尔蒙尼翁的纪律真是不可思议。
Because even though they're being overwhelmed, okay, they're being outnumbered,
因为即使他们被压倒，算是又被数目数数。
and they're about to be outrun, they hold their ground.
...
Okay? And then, in the right, in the center,
好的？然后，在右侧，在中间，
there's so much conflict that eventually what happens is there's a small gap
有这么多冲突，最终出现了一个小空隙，
that allows Alexander to rush to Darius.
让亚历山大得以冲到达里乌斯。
Okay? Remember, Darius is being protected heavily because he's the king.
好的？记住，达里乌斯被大力保护，因为他是王。
Right? And at this point,
对了？在此时，
Alexander and his forces are overwhelming the cavalry of Darius.
亚历山大与他的军队正好在此时相冲。
And they're about to close up.
他们即将接近。
They're getting close to Darius.
他们正好去到达里乌斯。
And at this point, what Darius does, and this is something you can never do in a battle.
在此时，D 里 空 空 ??
What does Darius do now? And he does this in both battles.
什么是达里乌斯现在做的事？他在两场战斗里都这么做。
Isis and Coromala.
伊斯司与科罗马洛？
What does he do now? He sees Alexander closing in, right?
他看到亚历山大正接近，才会…
But his left flank is about to overwhelm Parmonion.
但他左翼即将压倒帕尔蒙尼翁。
What does Darius do now?
什么是达里乌斯现在的动作？
In both battles? He runs away.
在两场战斗里都这么做。
He runs away. And when he does that,
他跑了。随后他这样做时，
Alexander is now free to go back
亚历山大此时可回去救帕尔蒙尼翁，随后又回到…
and rescue Parmonion, and then the Persians flee.
他人…
Okay? Does that make sense? All right.
好的？这有道理吗？好了。
So this is what happens in both battles, Isis and Coromala.
太好了！这两场战斗里，都是这般的情形。
So now that you have the basic overview of both battles,
先前……………………………………………………
let's analyze this to ask you,
让我们来分析一下，接着给你们…
let's ask ourselves, how great a commander is Alexander?
让我们来回顾一下…
Okay? And I want to make you, again, make the argument that he's actually not a great strategist.
此时…
Okay? He's a great soldier.
好的？他是个大将军。
He's very brave. But he's not a great strategist.
他很勇敢，能很久。
Not like his father. Okay? The first thing I will say is this.
...
When military historians look at battles, they look at the wrong things.
当军史学者看战斗时，先看了…
Right? So they're usually looking at manpower,
当军史学……
technology,
先后…
and resources.
和资源。
Okay? What we'll call wealth. Right?
好的，财富就是我们所说的。
And if we look at battles from this lens, right?
如果从这个角度看，能得出。”
Manpower, technology,
人类…
and resources, wealth, then
...
we can argue the Persians were heavily favored in this battle,
in this war. Right? We can say that.
在这场战争里，...
But I think this is the wrong way to look at military strategy.
...
I think if you really want to understand who's a favorite
and who's the underdog, you have to look at three different things.
和谁是下家，您要看三件事。
These three different things are cohesion.
这三件事是统一。
The idea of cohesion is unity.
…
Right? Are these soldiers loyal to each other?
对吗？这些士兵彼此之间忠诚吗？
Are they friends with each other? Okay?
他们彼此之间相互相互？好吧？
Second thing you want to look at is discipline.
第二个要点是…
How well trained are these troops?
这些部队训练有多好？
Okay? The third thing you want to look at is the idea of devotion.
好的？第三个要点是…
Devotion just means how loyal are they to the enemy.
奉…
How loyal are they to their leaders? How much purpose do they have in the battle?
...
Okay? Does that make sense? And what I want to show you today is,
look at these three things.
...
They give you a much better overview or analysis of
他们给你更好的概览或分析，…
who the better military is. Okay?
...
So, if you just look at manpower, technology,
and resources, then clearly the Persians are the heavy favorites.
和...
Right? But if you change your frame of reference,
...
and you will look at who's the most powerful, who has the most cohesion, discipline,
and devotion,
和奉献，随后马其顿人更为出色。对吧？因为看，凝聚力意味着他们有文化。
then the Macedonians are far superior.
和奉献，随后马其顿人更为出色。
Right? Because look, cohesion means they have a culture.
...
They have a similar culture. Right? They're all Greeks.
Whereas, the Persians are a multicultural empire.
...
They don't speak the same language, which means that
all these different units that Darius has, they're basically fighting by themselves.
所有这些多样的单位，达里乌斯拥有的，基本上是自己作战。
So, they are not coordinated. Okay?
...
Does that make sense? That's the first thing.
那算得了吗？那是第一件事。
Second thing is the idea of discipline.
第二个是...
If you're an empire, the problem with an empire is your soldiers don't fight
如果你是一个帝国，帝国的事物就是你士兵们不去打多场战斗。
that many battles. Right?
如果...
Because you're an empire. No one's going to challenge you.
因为你们是帝国，...
So, these soldiers, even though
...
they have these very expensive armor
他们有这些非常昂贵的盔甲
and horses, they weren't disciplined.
他们的士兵们也很久...
They didn't have experience in battle.
他们没有战斗经验。
Whereas, Alexander's army is Philip's army, and
他们的士兵们...
for the past 30 years, all they did was fight battle after battle against the Greeks.
过去30年，他们一直在与希腊作战，打完又打又回。
Okay? So, in terms of discipline,
好吧，士兵们士兵士…
the Greeks are far superior.
这…………??
And then you look at devotion. Darius is king.
然后你看着它的奉献...
Why are people loyal to him?
??……??…??…??…
Because he pays them.
??……??…??…
Right? It's profit. It's interest.
对吧？就是盈利。就是利益。
Whereas, the soldiers under Pommernion and
而且…士兵们在波莫尔尼翁的…
Alexander, they love their leaders.
亚历山大…士兵们很久…
Right? Their leaders have taken them to victory.
Right? ...
To victory. To lots of victories.
]}We need to translate cues 488-490. Provide JSON array translations. Eachstring may contain newline. Use simplified Chinese. Let's translate: 488:
So, they're very loyal to him. Okay? So, just in terms of these,
? Actually cue: [488] Right? Their leadershave taken them to victory. So translation:
if you just look at cohesion, discipline, and devotion,
如果你只看凝聚、纪律与奉献，我们就能预测亚历山大军队必胜。
we can predict that
如果你只看凝聚、协作与奉献，可得出亚历山大军势必胜。
Alexander's army would win regardless of the strategy.
...
Okay? And now, you can also make the argument that
the strategy that Alexander employed,
...
right, this, we will confront the Persians head on,
Philip would have thought this was a stupid idea.
菲利普会认为这是个愚笨的主意。
Okay? Because, first of all, you're outnumbered.
好的，先说一条：先前方先前方…
Second of all, you're on enemy terrain.
...
Right? You're on enemy terrain.
右？你在敌方阵地。
Therefore, they are able to deploy the resources much better than you are.
因此，能在此处部署资源更好。
Okay? Now, the third problem is this.
好的，先前方…
The third problem is you cannot afford to retreat.
503. 第三点：我方能否能……
Do you understand? There's no place to retreat.
...
If your army ever breaks, right,
……
if Pommernion gets overwhelmed, then you're all dead.
如果波莫尔尼翁被压倒，便是全军已完毕。
Why take that risk?
?
Right? Because you're not going to be able to retreat. Also, before our full battle,
it is in Gargamola, Darius wants to negotiate with Alexander.
它在加尔加莫拉，达里乌斯想和亚历山大谈判。
Basically, Darius said, I will give you half my empire.
基本上，达里波尔说：我给你半个帝国。
Right? That's pretty generous.
好吧，给我方…
And Alexander says, no, I need all of it.
512. 译文：并且亚历山大说：...??
Right? So,
]}
historians will tell you that Gargamola is,
?
just shows the military prowess of Alexander.
只展示了亚历山大军力的强大。
And, but if you analyze it properly, I think, you will see their lives are in danger.
而且若把它分析得当时，便可得出其一百个…
They have lots of problems with Alexander's strategy in both battles.
他在两场战斗里都有点…
Okay? He was taking risks that he shouldn't have.
518. 译文：好的？我方…??
And, he sacrificed a lot of men that he didn't really need to sacrifice.
518????????????????????????????????????????…
For example, it was all about winning the war, right,
???…
personal glory, whereas Philip was concerned about the safety
个人的荣耀，而菲利普则关注士兵的安全与福祸。
and well -being of his soldiers.
菲利普的士兵士兵士兵…
So, Philip would not have engaged in such a battle.
...
He would have preferred negotiation. And, then, over time, slowly,
他会更喜欢谈判…
overwhelmed Persia.
...……………………………………
Does that make sense?
…………………………
Any questions so far? About this analysis?
已翻译的字幕1
Quick question. Yeah, great.
已翻译的字幕2
I think you just you are fighting for power, right?
已翻译的字幕原文
Yeah. You said it was a very big turning
against other states, right?
译文1
That must put you stressed about things like the and
译语句
Yeah. Right.
呀！好！
Great question.
So, actually they didn't really trust the Greeks.
所以，实际上他们并不真正信任希腊人。
The Greeks didn't consider the Macedonians part of
希腊人没能
they didn't consider the Macedonians Greek.
译文1
And so when
译前
Alexander sent his when
亚历山大派遣他时
Alexander developed his invasion force of Persia, there weren't that many Greeks actually in it.
亚历山大组建入侵波斯军团，希腊人已不多
It was mostly Macedonian. Does that make sense?
它大多是马其人。这样算吗？
You're right. Given what Alexander did to Thebes,
你说得对。给定了个别的那点儿。”
he couldn't really trust the Greeks anymore.
他能不能再把希腊人当作一份…
He couldn't really trust the Greeks to switch sides.
先前……
And also there were a lot of Greek mercenaries fighting for Darius in this battle.
还有很多希腊人雇兵在这场战斗中为大里乌打战
Menon of Rhodes was Greek.
鲁德斯的门农是希腊人
And he sort of knew the Greeks really didn't like Alexander.
他大概会有点儿，跟随了个别的…
So it was more like a tribal army rather than a material army.
}]
That's right. But
...
again, we see this throughout history where a tribal army, because of cohesion discipline and devotion,
they were able to conquer the world, right?
他们能征服世界，没错吗？
So you look Yeah,
又...
yeah. So you look at Mohammed, you look at Genghis Khan,
呀！...
and you look at Tamerlan, you look at a lot of people, right?
...
They were all tribal armies, but because they had cohesion,
discipline, and devotion, they were able to basically conquer most of the world
...
before they themselves devolved into civil war.
在...前，...又...
Okay? Does that make sense?
...
Any more questions before I continue?
还有什么问题吗？
Okay. Okay.
好的。
Okay, so while
...
Alexander was campaigning against Persia, he was doing things
that sort of annoyed his soldiers, okay?
那种事让他的士兵们有点儿烦，行吗？
So for example, he conquered Egypt without much resistance.
比如说，他在埃及征服时没啥抵挡。
So he went to Egypt, and basically the Egyptians hated the Persians.
于是他去到埃及，基本上埃及人就把波斯人当成了。
For decades, for centuries,
几百年，几百年，
the Egyptians were trying to rebel against Persia without success.
埃及人曾经常尝试反抗波斯，才好？
So when Alexander came, they saw him as a liberator.
...
So Egypt felt without resistance.
埃及无抵挡。
The first thing that Alexander does is he takes a trip into the desert.
他在埃及的第一件事就是去旅行到沙漠里。
He disappears for weeks.
他在几周里消失。
He goes to something called, he goes to a place called the temple
他去了一处叫做的地方，去了一处叫做的地方，去了一处叫做的地方，去了个…
of Zeus, Amon.
他去到…
Amon is the highest Egyptian god, and Zeus is the highest Greek god.
...
So they are like a synthesis, okay?
他们像是合成的，好的？
So this is the highest god in the world.
这是最上层的神，...
And this is found in the, I say, Oasis.
在这……
And Alexander goes to this Oasis in order to seek counsel.
我想要...??
He wants to see his future. And at,
?
when he's at the temple of Zeus, Amon,
he's told that
他被告知菲利普并非他的亲生父亲。
Philip is not really his father.
菲利普是个别的…
Okay? Philip is not really his father.
...
Alexander's true father is,
??
take a wild guess, who the true father is.
取个大概的猜测，谁是最真的吗？
Zeus, Amon, right? Alexander is the first son of God,
取个大概…
right? He's the son of God.
右？他是上帝之子。
He's like Heracles and Dionysus.
他像赫尔克勒斯和狄尼奥斯。
He's actually the son of God.
...
And so, when Alexander returns
to his soldiers after this revelation,
给他士兵们的这番揭示后，
he expects his soldiers to acknowledge this fact, okay?
他期望他们能承认这件事，
So one thing is,
译文1
in the Macedonian army,
译文2
there's a lot of equality between soldiers
有很多士兵与军官之间的平等
and officers, right?
有点儿士兵与军官们的相互相等
So if you're a soldier, you are allowed to speak your mind.
译文1
But now, Alexander demands,
译文2
if you come into his presence, you must first kiss his feet.
如果你来到他的面前，先要吻他的脚。
Which is the Persian custom, okay?
它是个别名的古希腔语？
You must first, you must kiss the feet of your king.
先前方可口语??
And the Macedonians, of course, didn't really like this.
当然，马其人们并不太喜欢这件事。
So now there's growing concern
于是现在有了更大之意。
about the tyranny of Alexander.
关于亚历山大之王之事。
Okay? People like Parmonion
好的？人们喜欢帕尔蒙尼恩
and Cletus of Black, who were promoted heavily by his father, are kind of annoyed.
和黑色的克莱特斯，先前方可口语??
Basically, Alexander renounced his father.
基本上，亚历山大先前方可口语??
Philip's not really my father. I'm really the son of a god, okay?
菲利普并不是我的父亲，我是神之子，行吗？
Zeus, Amon. Okay?
泽乌斯，阿蒙，行吗？
So, okay.
好，算了！
So now there's growing discontent among his soldiers.
现在…………………
Does that make sense so far?
...??……??
Any questions before I move on?
...????
Is this clear to you?
Is this clear toyou?
Okay? Alright.
]}We need to translate cue [615]
So, you know, in 331 BCE,
...
the Battle of Gorgomola happens and Alexander wins this
Gorgomola战役发生，亚历山大赢得了这场胜利…
incredible victory against the Persian king, Darius.
...
Darius runs away, but then
达里亚逃走，随后…
he's eventually killed by one of his generals, okay?
他终于在此时…
And the Persian empire now is basically
和…
conquered. There's no resistance against Alexander anymore.
...
There's some resistance, but not organized resistance.
Okay? And at this point,
...
Alexander starts being a tyrant.
亚历山大开始变成霸主。
Okay? So the first major
translation2
sign that he's changing is in 330 BCE,
在 330 年前后，变更的标志是…
Parmonion is killed. Remember, Parmonion, you can argue,
...
was the man responsible for all of Alexander's victories, right?
他是负责亚历山大所有胜利的人，对吧？
Because Parmonion is the one who's doing all the heavy lifting.
因为帕尔蒙尼翁是那位负责大部分工作的人。
He's being overwhelmed by most of Persian forces.
他正被帕尔蒙尼翁的全体…
He stands his ground, which allows Alexander
他在此立足，便可让亚历山大声称胜利，嗯？
to claim his victory, okay?
We have…………………………………………………
In 330 BCE,
?
Alexander orders Parmonion to be killed.
亚历山大下令帕尔蒙尼翁被杀
And there's a lot of controversy around what happened, right?
...
So I'll just basically tell you the basic
facts, and then we'll analyze what happened.
事实，然后我们分析发生的事。
So, there's a lot of
事实与我们分析发生的事。
resentment against Alexander in the army.
对军中对亚历山大的怨恨。
And now and then there are these conspiracies.
以及此时此刻的几次阴谋。
They don't go anywhere. But
他们不去任何地方。但有些军官之间的阴谋要杀亚历山大。
there are these conspiracies amongst officers to assassinate Alexander.
他们不去任何地方，且军官们间的阴谋去往来回去。
And one of these conspiracies
翻译1
is found out, and
]}We need to translate cues 644 and 645. They are: [644] And one of these conspiracies [645] is found out, and. We need to produce JSON with translations array of two strings. Use Chinese translation. Use terms:
one of the officers who finds out about this conspiracy goes to
其中一名军官发现此阴谋后去向帕尔蒙尼翁之子汇报。
Parmonion's son, okay?
随后再去向帕尔蒙尼…
And tells the son, hey,
...
go tell the king people are trying to assassinate him.
The son, Parmonion's son,
...
he doesn't think this is a big deal.
And he's kind of drunk, okay?
...
So he doesn't, he forgets to tell Alexander, okay?
他在此时...
The plot is uncovered, and the son,
?
Philolitus, Philolitus,
he's implicated, and he's tortured.
他被牵涉，且被折腾。
He had nothing to do with the assassination, but he's implicated.
他有没能与之发起发起发起？
Because he didn't tell Alexander.
其…
While he's being tortured,
在他被折腾时，
he also confesses to his father being part of the plot,
他也承认他父亲参与了阴谋，
even though there's no evidence implicating his father.
即使得其父亲没有可用的证据。
In fact, you can make the argument that his father is completely loyal to Alexander.
在此，您可以根据此类推断：他父亲完全相继于亚历山大。
Okay? And so, just based on this,
]}We need to translate cues 662-664. Provide JSON with translations array. Each string may contain at most one newline. Use simplified Chinese. Use terms: father=父亲. Let's translate each cue in order. Provide array of 3 translations. Ensure no extra keys. Let's craft translations. Cue 662:
a forced confession under torture, which is completely unreliable,
]} seems incomplete. Actually cue 662:
Alexander and the army decide to have Parmonion killed, okay?
亚历山大与军队决定杀死帕尔蒙尼翁，好的？
So an assassin is sent, and Parmonion is killed.
于是派人刺杀，帕尔蒙尼翁被杀死。
Now, these are the basic facts.
现在，这些是基本事实。
And there's a lot of argument about what happened, okay?
...
So the most generous argument, the most generous interpretation
is Alexander didn't want Parmonion killed.
...
He knows Parmonion
他知道帕尔蒙尼翁是无辜的，但因亚历山大被迫使得以太子去世，才有了“以太子”之名。
is innocent, but because Alexander was forced to kill his son,
...】}We need to translate cues 671-673. Provide translations array with 3 strings. Use simplified Chinese. Ensure terms: Parmonion, Philolitus? Actually
Philolitus, Alexander didn't feel he had a choice in the matter,
? Wait. Let's parse: cue 671:
okay? Because Parmonion might want revenge.
...
So to maintain
stability and peace within the army,
...
he had to get Parmonion killed, okay?
That's the most generous explanation. But there's another explanation
???
that makes more sense, which is
???????????????????????????????
Alexander has always been jealous of Parmonion, right?
亚历山大一直很羡慕帕尔蒙尼翁，没错吧？
Because Parmonion has the most legitimacy in the army.
因为帕尔蒙尼翁在军队里有最好的
Troops feel more loyal to Parmonion than they do to Alexander.
部队更倾向于帕尔蒙尼翁，而非亚历山大。
Right? Because they've been, they've, uh,
部队更倾向…???????????????????????????????????????????????????????
Parmonion, um, they're more experienced with Parmonion than with Alexander.
帕尔蒙尼翁，嗯…我想他更有经验与帕尔蒙...
And Parmonion was responsible for many great triumphs.
...
So Alexander was jealous of Parmonion.
亚历山大羡慕帕尔蒙尼翁。
Also, there were these new young officers who wanted to climb the ranks.
还有…………………………
And to do so, they needed to get rid of people like Parmonion, right?
为了完成这一点，他们需要先除掉像帕尔蒙尼翁的人，没错吗？
So maybe the conspiracy was
...??
a fake conspiracy and
翻译成...??
it was organized by these law officers to implicate Philolitus,
?
and then in order to get rid of
翻译成...??
Parmonion, okay? But
翻译成??
regardless of how you interpret this,
]}We need to translate cues 692-694. Provide JSON translations array. Each string may contain newline. Let's translate: cue 692:
what we do know is, after Parmonion was killed,
...??
basically all the shackles, all the restraints on Alexander went away.
??
Because there's no one in the, because now there's no one in the army who
can resist Alexander, okay?
可以抵挡亚历山大，好的？
There's no one who
还有一个人
can basically urge restraint and caution.
基本上可以促使...
So the next thing that happens is this.
所以接下来发生的事就是这样。
In the year 328,
在 328 年，
Cleitus the Black is killed.
清晰的...
Remember, Cleitus the Black is the person who
记得，清晰的…
saved Alexander's life at the Battle of Branacus, okay?
...……………
But Cleitus the Black, again, he is a loyal officer promoted by his father.
…………
And now Cleitus the Black has the same authority
现在，清晰的黑色拥有与帕尔莫尼翁相同的权力。
as Parmonion once had.
现在的清晰…
So Cleitus the Black is now a threat to Alexander.
...
So what Alexander does is,
所以亚历山大所做的事是，
he basically orders Cleitus the Black to take some soldiers and go off
他把清晰的黑色归一百个…
to a faraway place. It's basically exile, okay?
其…
Alexander is basically exiling him from the main army.
亚历山大基本把他从主力军队中驱逐出去。
And Cleitus the Black knows, basically, he's finished.
清晰的黑色知道他已完工。
So before Cleitus the Black is meant to go into exile,
?
they have a large banquet, okay?
...
And they're all drunk. And Cleitus the Black now is angry.
And he gets into a vicious argument
...
with Alexander. And
Cleitus the Black basically says, to Alexander,
翻译：
you've betrayed your people, the Macedonians.
...
You've come to Persia,
and you could only conquer Persia without our help.
...
And now you're turning into a Persian, okay?
You're adopting Persian customs, like forcing officers to kiss your feet.
你正在采用...
You're promoting Persian officers within your army.
...
Okay? You're turning your back away from the culture that made you great.
Then, he says something that really
...
pisses Alexander off. What is one thing that you can say to Alexander that would really piss him off?
In fact, he would want to kill you now.
...
Everything that you've achieved, Alexander,
it's because of your father. This is not you, okay?
...
This conquest of Persia, it's not you.
It's your father.
...
It's your father who built this amazing army.
它是你父亲建造了这支惊人军队。
It's your father who developed this plan to conquer Persia.
它是你父亲开发了这道工兵征服波斯的计划。
Okay? Alexander gets so angry that
好的？亚历山大愤怒至...
he's about to lunge at Cleitus the Black, okay?
好的，亚历...
But before he can do so, his party guard
但在他能做之前，...
surrounds him and stops him, and they pull away his sword.
...
And so this makes us think, he's been doing this a lot, okay?
和...这让我们想，他已经做了很多次，好吗？
Alexander the Great gets drunk a lot and kills a lot of people, basically.
亚历山大大...??
Um, and then Cleitus the Black, he's taken out of the room.
嗯，随后亚历山大把克利图斯·黑色放进房间。
But Cleitus the Black is so strong, he forces himself back in the room.
嗯，后...
He starts to continue arguing against Alexander.
...
Alexander then goes and takes a spear
and throws it at Cleitus the Black, killing him on the spot.
...
So, Cleitus the Black is now dead.
The two men who are most responsible for
...
Alexander's victories in Persia are now both dead.
Okay? And he's becoming more
好的？他正变得更...
and more of a tyrant.
...
Um, soon afterwards,
嗯，随后，
there's a conspiracy, there's a real conspiracy to kill him.
有一个阴谋，接着是个大阴谋要杀他。
What happens is this, okay?
...
Uh, the king, Alexander,
uh, goes on a boar hunt
嗯，跟着他去狩猎...
with his pages, okay?
嗯...
His servants. Now, the custom in Persia is
他的仆从。现在，波斯里有个回到…
the king has the right to the first kill.
...
But these are, but his pages are Macedonian, so they don't know this.
So one of the pages is the first to kill the boar.
...
Alexander is so angry, he beats him.
阿尔谢尔·波波波...
He beats the crap out of this page.
...
The pages get together that night, and
they resolve to kill, kill this tyrant.
...
And, um, they develop, they,
they, they organize a schedule so that
...
on one night, they will be all in the bedroom, looking after Alexander while he sleeps.
在某个夜晚，他们全部在卧室里守着亚历山大，等他睡着。
And then, and then of course they will take out their their daggers and stab Alexander to death, okay?
随后，若干百人之中，百里…
That's the plan. What happens is, that
那是计划！
night, they were supposed to do this act, Alexander goes out drinking.
那夜里，...
He gets drunk, and he does not come back until
他喝醉后，等到早晨才回到…
the early morning when the pages are gone, okay?
他喝醉后，等到早时…
At this point, one of the pages gets nervous, and
在此时，某个页面…
tells Alexander about the conspiracy, and Alexander has everyone killed, okay?
在此…
But during the trial, the pages accuse Alexander of being a tyrant.
...
Okay? Does that make sense? Then, what happens is,
OK? 这点儿…
in 326 BCE,
在326年BCE…
after Alexander has conquered all Persia,
after Alexander hasconquered all Persia,
he decides to take his army to India, okay?
他决定把他的军队带到印度，好吗？
Now, his army is not happy about this because,
现在，军队…
look, there are lots of good reasons to invade Persia, right?
The first reason is, Persia is very wealthy.
??
Second reason is, um,
第二个原因是，嗯，
Persia invaded Greece,
第一个…??
right? So Greece, so Persia was always a threat to the Greece, the Greek mainland.
对吗？所以希腊，希腊是一直威胁到希腊本土的。
The third reason is, there are lots of people who suspect it was the Persians
??
who killed Philip, okay? So there's lots of good reasons to invade Persia.
谁杀了菲利普？好吧？所以有很多好理由去入侵波斯。
There's actually no reason to invade India, okay?
有点儿…
They've never been to India, they have actually no idea
他们曾经去过?
what they will find in India. It's a different geography, okay?
...
But in, but Alexander forces his forces,
但在，亚历山大把他的军队...
his army, to invade India, in basically modern -day Pakistan.
...
And there, they win these victories,
翻译：在那里，他们赢得了这些胜利。
but the soldiers are
...
really pissed off because they're far away from home,
really pissed off becausethey're far away from home,
they have absolutely no idea when this war will end,
...
and the weather in India really sucks, okay?
在...??
So they basically mutiny, they refuse to fight.
...
And Alexander at this point has no choice
but to give in to the,
but to retreat, okay?
但他又做了两件事来证明他的愤怒。
To return back to Babylon.
他把所有士兵们的士兵们…
But he does two things to show his anger.
但他又做了两件事来证明他的愤怒。
The first thing he does is, he kills all the leaders of the mutiny, okay?
第一件事是，给了他那几百个??
Those who spoke up on behalf of their fellow soldiers were all killed, one by one.
那些在前面发声的士兵一一发出??
So the second thing that happens is,
??
rather than take his soldiers back the original way,
[809] 先后??
Alexander made them march through a desert, which
[810] 先后??
killed many of them, okay?
已杀了许多的他，好的？
Many died because of dehydration and starvation.
许多百个??
It was a brutal march across the desert.
它是一次穿越沙漠的繁复行军。
So, Alexander takes his army back to Babylon,
??
and at this point,
在此时，亚历山大决定他可以不进印度，于是去进军到阿拉伯。
Alexander decides he can't invade India, so he'll go invade Arabia,
亚历山大决定他能去进军到阿拉伯，又可回到回去回去??】】】】】】】】】】】】】??】】??】???】???】?】??????】?????????】?????????】…】】?】??????????????????}】?}】?】?????????1?…?】?????{
okay? He'll go invade Arabia, which is desert.
}}?????????{
There's a reason why no one invaded Arabia, and the reason why it's all desert.
有一个...??
There's no reason to invade
???..???
Arabia. But Alexander wants to be the first to conquer Arabia,
????..???
because his ambition is boundless, okay?
因为他的雄心无边，好的？
He has to prove he's the greatest conqueror in the world.
他要证明自己是世界最伟大的征服者。
The only way he can do that is by conquering the entire world.
他只要去往前方去。”
He's very suspicious of his own soldiers, because they mutiny against him in India, right?
So he's starting to replace his army with Persians, who are much more obedient.
??
He wants obedience. Then
something else happens. Back in Macedonia,
something else...
the general in charge, Antepater, who
...
again is one of
Philip's most loyal generals,
菲利普最忠诚的将领们，
he gets into an argument with Olympias, okay?
他与奥林匹亚斯发生争论，好的？
Olympias answers his mother, and Antepater don't see eye to eye.
奥林匹亚斯回答他的母亲，和安特帕特尔不见相同。
And Olympias tells Alexander, and Alexander
奥林匹亚斯告诉亚历山大，亚历山大邀请安特帕特尔去巴比伦，等候在此处处理事务，好的？
invites Antepater to Babylon, where they will settle matters, okay?
安特帕特尔知道了百里安那尔里奥尔的事情。”}]}The task: translate cues 833-835 into Simplified Chinese. Provide JSON array translations. Must be natural Chinese subtitles. Use preferred terms.Let's translate each cue separately, keep order. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Let's produce Chinese lines. Let's craft translations: cue 833:
And Antepater knows what happened to Parmenion.
? Wait cue 833:
He knows what happened to Clytus the Black.
翻译1
And at this point,
翻译2
most of Alexander's generals are unhappy with the fact
翻译3
that the army is being Persianized, right?
...
They're being replaced by Persian officers who are more loyal
翻译1
to Alexander. So in 323,
翻翻译2
Alexander dies.
亚历山大去世。
And again, no one will ever know what actually happened,
再一次，谁也不曾知晓其实情。
but the theory is this, okay?
翻译1
I think the theory that
翻译2
makes the most sense is basically the top echelon of the Macedonian army,
译文1
Antepater and the other generals, basically decided Alexander has to go
译前翻译1
because he's a tyrant.
因为他是个暴君。
And eventually, he's going to kill everyone, okay?
而且终于会把他人一一去掉。
So what happened was there was a banquet, and Antepater and his son,
于是，宴席里有个…
he's the cupbearer to Alexander, the person
...
who pours the drinks to Alexander during meals.
谁在餐时给亚历山大倒酒？
The son puts poison in the cup.
亚历山大之子把酒杯里装满了酒
Alexander drinks from it, and he starts to vomit, okay?
亚历山大喝下后开始呕吐，好吗？
So Alexander leaves the room to vomit.
亚历山大离开房间去呕吐。
And then the son, Antepater's son,
而后又是个…
brings a feather laced with more poison to help Alexander vomit some more,
带来一根羽毛，塞满了更多的毒药，帮助亚历山大再呕吐一次，
okay? But, and so Alexander should have died on the spot.
...好吧，咱们来个别的…??
But Alexander is so tough, he's such a strong man,
,
that he lasts for a few more weeks, okay?
那他还在几周后才结束，好吗？
And he dies in bed. So Alexander now is
他在床上去世，算是吧？
dead. Okay?
好吧，算算…
Okay, this is important because
好的，...??
even though he's dead, in the ten years
...???
that he's been around, he's been able to conquer most of the world, which includes Egypt,
...????
Mesopotamia,
美索不达米亚，
Iran, Afghanistan, Pakistan.
伊朗、阿富尔干、巴基斯坦。
Okay? He's able to conquer most of the known world.
好的？他能征服已知世界的大部分。
And this creates a problem for the generals
869. 这就算作…??
who succeed him. Right?
]}We need to translate cues 869-871. Provide translations array with 3 strings. Use simplified Chinese. Ensure line breaks natural. Let's translate: 869:
Because once you conquer most of this world, and remember,
. Actually cue 869 text:
the plan was not to conquer most of the world.
第六个...??
It was just Alexander's balanced ambition that made them do so, okay?
?
Another question is how do you govern?
And so because of this pressure,
...
they have no choice but to
???
develop something called Greek culture
and spread it in order to create legitimacy for themselves.
and spread…………………………………………………
Okay? And this is something that we will talk about
?
next class, which will conclude
下节课，随后会结束
our session on the Greeks, okay?
下节课，随后会…
The legacy of Alexander. He's conquered the world, and now his generals must govern it.
亚历山大遗产。他征服了世界，现在他的将军们要去统治它。
And to govern it, they must use something called Greek culture.
亚历士兵军士兵…
So they must invent Greek culture, and then spread it around the world.
译文1
And when they do so, what will happen is,
译句
the Greek culture will merge with local cultures to create new ideas,
希腓文化会与当地文化融合，产生新思想，
okay? Greek culture,
希腓文化…
one of these cultures that Greek culture will merge with is called Judaism.
犹太文化。
Judaism. And when
犹太文化与…
these two cultures merge, a new idea will emerge
这两种文化融合，新的想法诞生。
from this mixture called Christianity
从这混合而来，...
that changes the world forever, okay?
...
That's why Christians love Alexander the Great, because they feel that without his conquest,
Christianity could not have been born, okay?
...
So there are many Christians who feel like Alexander the Great, yeah,
he was a tyrant, but he was part of God's plan.
他是个暴君，但他是上帝计划的一部分。
He was all part of a plan. He did what he did because he truly is
他是计划的一部分。他做了那件事，因他真是…
the son of Zeus Amon, and Zeus Amon commanded him to conquer the world.
the son of Zeus Amon, and Zeus Amoncommanded him to conquer the world.
Okay? But again, that is a Christian perspective.
...
Alright, so that is it, okay?
So let's review what we did today.
...
We basically looked at this analytical model,
我们基本上看了这个分析模型，
and we made three predictions about Alexander based on this analytical model, right?
我们在此基础上做出了三条预测，关于亚历山大，
The first is that he would focus on expansion,
第一条预测是：他会去做…
second is he would become a tyrant, and the third is that he would never stop expanding.
第二条是他会成为暴君，第三条是他会一直扩张。
And it turns out, he was exactly like this, okay?
他又一次又回到这点，跟上面那句…
This explains, this predicts his life in time.
…
Alright? So, any questions?
好的？还有什么问题？
Okay. So, next class,
好的，下一节课
what we will do is we will look at
我们要看
the spreading of Greek culture and the building of the Hellenistic world.
希腊文化的扩散与希腊世界的建构。
Okay? And that will end our section on the Greeks.
好的？我们这回合了？